Oh
yeah conversation with Johnny V yeah
yeah the pardon would you enjoy about it
well the the place where the the logos
became aware of itself it was what I
enjoyed about it and then the this the
sort of the movements around in that
space I felt a lot of energy coming in
to me I felt quite enthusiastic about
that punk point in the conversation and
in the fact that in the Apple in the
conversation you were talking about the
people who would be potentially the
presence of the people who potentially
watched him that conversation right of
which of course I was a member and
feeling what that means the implications
of that which touched on
the memory of the fact that you and I
had talked about that in our previous
conversation which then ignited that
whole train of thought all right right
because it it does seem to me that
there's
a big part of this for me that I'm
noticing is just it's like a kind of
almost an autonomous presence I'm
walking around with these conversations
through the day on some level right it's
it's always almost
it's a little bit like I was just
thinking about this Gregory Bateson
talked about the difference between like
a blockbuster movie and an in an art
movie or more artful movie and what he
says is like with a blockbuster movie
right you walk in one way and you sit
down and there's like the beginning
right the build up the peak the climax
the crescendo and the ending and the
happy story and and then you walk back
out the same way as he walked in but
like the more artful he would say the
more artful the movie is the more you
engage in like a narrative and in that
it leaves you on some level incomplete
right it doesn't do all the work for you
right so lately so it's so that's where
art it can be something where you walk
out walk in one way and you walk out
with the new paradox or tension that you
live with right and you enact out and
you see the world differently mm-hmm and
I think there's something about these
conversations personally and I think
it's is John would say that the dial
logos in general in my life when it's
sufficiently intense or real or has a
particular quality to it has it has this
quality of like that I leave with these
new tensions and twists on things that
are not totally complete but are are
present in there in completion right I
guess that sense of inexhaustible
intelligibility at new levels is
revealed more of the ground is revealed
but like also more ground thus the
horizon is revealed and in some level I
think I'm
in ways that I don't even think I'm
probably conscious of all the time it
becomes kind of a little bit like it
just the soundtrack of the movie of my
life right which is this so there's a
level of which I'm consciously thinking
about the thoughts that we just had but
there's another level where it's there
they're thoughts that seem to do they
seem to affect the soundtrack of the
movie which is
one second yeah let's grab an envelope
you were going to see a brief cameo and
the movie of your life awesome
this is his guy Vanessa he says very
very good things about you letting you
know that I say good things about you
very very good things about you I'm
sorry I have as you might imagine been
completely drawn out of the threat of
our stage good mmm some some some words
that were bouncing around in my mind as
you're talking with something along the
lines they like a concerto played out on
the like a serendipity keyboard in your
life where you know the soundtrack of
your life but it's like the events the
moments that you encounter suddenly have
this new possibility that opens up and
so for example I was visiting a Waldorf
School this morning and you might
imagine that the conversations that I've
had with you and John with others over
the past few days are sort of always
there and they're dancing with each
other why they're always moving and
dance with each other but they're also
dancing with the flow of experience that
I'm going through yeah so events were
suddenly popping up in the context of
this experience of just watching these
kids playing and learning and listening
in the smells and I was just having
moments or perspectives in the
conversations that I had perhaps
perceived I had not sensed it had not
made any meaning out of that we just
dropped in these moments of Epiphany pop
pop pop they would moving back and forth
there's a dialogue in time between the
flow of experience that I was in at the
moment and the flow of experience that I
had been through thus far what was it
yeah so it was like that the concerto on
the piano of the keyboard of Epiphany
was the phrase the popped into my head
mm-hmm there's a really interesting
distinction that you made I don't want
to I want to ask you about the east
talked about the difference between
I think he said they have been thoughts
in my mind but hadn't yet become part of
the flow of experience in the world
he made a distinction about that right
where what I recall all I mean I mean
two distinctions window sting I just
thought was between the flow of
experience that I was in in the moment
and then the flow of experience that I
had been coming into relation with each
other and so the the the becoming of me
as a consequence of the constitutive
experiences that I have this already had
the past moving into the present and in
the future coming towards me through the
present and there's two pieces you know
like cream being poured into coffee in
the the missile is a the missile a
should have been between each other and
then the other side was the distinction
between perception and sensing mmm-hmm
meaning and noticing that there are mmm
my do I have bad network connection I'm
yeah bummer yeah either that or you've
been doing strange meditations lately I
did that to my parents we're doing doing
a call and the internet connection was
quite sketching I would just stop
and my around okay we couldn't tell
whether or not it actually frozen with
roaches Appendix A so the previous point
was something along the lines of there's
always a massive reduction from
perception to sensing there's just so
much flow coming in that's available for
sensing but it's not in fact attended to
in sensor but as you're moving into new
experiences those new experiences might
create yeah would it be maybe a wait
maybe awaits the right kind of metaphor
or a actually the image that I have is
that thing you're trying to see like a
spider web you can't see it until you
move your eyes and so you had just the
right refraction with where there's
light glinting off of it and then it
pops out something like so the flow of
experience creates a sort of a
diffraction that allows a piece of
perception that was previously on sense
that was already there to pop out which
then drops more fully into the
possibility of meaning for example yeah
keep them and thinking about the this
sense of being is connection to
perception sensing in the the the notion
of that something like what we call
ourselves is being a kind of it's being
[Music]
is you could say it finds its being in
its in its absence
like like the way the womb is absent
right and that there's a way like
phenomenologically like with perception
which toads get goes into this somebody
who really took off on the work that
that actually john i sent me this book
this this working out the problem of how
the hell do we actually get to know the
world
perception right like and he has this
way of talking about it that there's a
way in which desire or absence right in
a certain sense creates a kind of
[Music]
whoom in which perception is like a
pregnancy right like coming into
perception is the kind of being a leg up
being impregnated by the world and so
kind of just thinking about this this
sense of in really rich conversations
and these dialogues that were having
that if if somehow the dialogue touches
on like presuppositions who are just but
like like adjust presuppositions that I
kind of sit on that that allow me to
desire whatever it is that I desire that
then have me notice what I notice but
then we have a conversation that
actually alters mmm on that I'm on now I
start to desire things that I didn't
even the warrant even possible before to
desire so I'll notice new things as a
couple with the world in some way mhm
yeah yeah and there's talking to Jenna
and I spoke about yesterday those things
are very difficult to keep track of
aren't they so what came to my mind as
you as you're talking about what this
was just the who so there's the being of
a particular stack let's just use that
as a metaphor and there's the awareness
of that particular stack yeah and then
there's the actual ability to be in a
relationship with that particular stack
which are all those aren't the same
thing so the being of the stack includes
he was just mentioning I think you and
he actually talked about this he was
mentioning Hume and how Hughes
embodiment the way his he actually
related his body to the act of thinking
that he would sit very still like he was
he was almost frozen in place so his
body was minute was maximally not
playing a role in the thought and the
dis fact
presupposes a quality of possibility
that the kinds of thoughts that you can
have are already in many ways prefigured
by that choice where if you were to say
for example be moving just that simple
thing just the fact that your body
pre-exists the thinking that you're
having the relationship of your body to
what's happening is is sort of
primordial in that stack and as you say
there's a set of when there's a whole
bunch of stuff right there's disposition
what's going on within the context of my
whole bio system and in all the
different ways that it can be that will
have the same effect and then what is
the mapping that I've already got at a
more hardware level like I know that I
did a period of time where I was I was
fasting and one of the things that I
noticed was the way that there was these
layers between a sensation and then a
notion of what that sensation meant and
then an intention of what that is
sensation sensations meaning implied for
how to respond and so I'd have some bio
biological sensation and then I would
notice for example that I would have
almost immediately like an image pop
into my head I would say like chocolate
or whatever and and in the act of
fasting because by virtue of fasting I
was actually imposing discipline on my
choices so that it didn't happen you
know and people have done this many
different ways but posture does this in
the context of meditation that those
those relationships were fluid of course
right you can begin to decompose and you
can be in to actually be able to be
aware of just the sensation without even
moving to the level of its what it means
I'm sure that without moving to the
level of what it intends and double
certain level without acting on that
intention so there's something there as
well that I was hearing what you were
saying yeah yeah there's just this
so much going on always already isn't
there yeah yeah is so much going on
always already just like we shut like I
show up there is this quality of
experience which I when I meditate
oftentimes I'll see if I can actually
just kind of be present to this right
which is actually what the level of the
quality of presence that can come about
just by focusing on this which is this
sense of having always already begun
every time I go and find myself I'm
already there to find this this this
already begun this mm-hmm
and in it you can feel that in your like
when you like in papasa de for example
like the Glinka style Posada where
you're just feeling the get like kind of
the quality of givenness of sensation
that there is this this interesting
experience of for me sometimes when I
can really tap into that quality of
givenness that there's this this level
where first just starts off as just like
okay the sensation okay it's emerging
okay it's already happening right it's
already there and then there's this
quality where is you start to focus on
that then there's this quality of that
and the awareness of it happening is
already there as given and this mr sztyc
i think starts to get into some of this
this sense of the primordial ground that
you mentioned which is this movement of
history that even has me have the
concepts that i have the desires that i
have the the posture I'm sitting in the
intelligibility that has me kind of meet
the moment in that moment on some level
I arrived already begun in this
particular way and meet and meet the
world there's something about that that
is
I think in our last conversation I was
really left with
that sense of both the sense of it but
also through you with you aware and
touched by the like the danger of
misinterpreting what that is right and
and
in which is really interesting have you
I wanted to read actually some of the
comments from the video which I was
really quite struck by um some of these
comments
let me just pull that up really quick
[Music]
you
mmm okay so there's uh mmm we're great
by the way just popped into my head so
just as a flag
sit let's pull in that flag a little bit
cuz that it was preceded with a - mmm
yeah yeah
there was a deepening and a deepening so
the first thing that was happening was
the awareness of what the implications
are of what you're about to do or what
you're an act do it by bringing in the
comments into the conversation you're
expanding the conversation right you're
doing something that is shifting the
nature with the scope for skiing l or
space or consciousness - the
conversation is and then there was a
annexation the word realization here is
like dawn of the the way or the how of
noticing a myself actually as we were
kind of moving through the conversation
of feeling in myself of what's actually
even happening here and noticing that as
I like move my conscious awareness to
different aspects of myself that what
was happening at its highest level the
thing that was most potent the most
promising was the the flowing or the
fluidity of listening she was a membrane
of what I was encountering again this
sort of this this relationship between
the the outside and the inside of the
relationship between a sovereign world
and then listening to that and then also
a myself listening to myself and
learning or trying to find a way to
actually orient or shift my way of being
in relationship to it was happening and
then I had this pop of noticing that
then if you if you expanded the the
comments there's a this thing that's
constantly recurring which is the the
the flows or the consciousnesses that
are participating in a moment in event
and then there's the grace which is to
say the the artfulness
of the wholeness in relationship with
the highest or the furthering of the
movement of the event something like
that if you just think about kind of
that to do
meaning of Graces like the ability for
there to be a directed intentional
movement that it has a characteristic of
smoothness and poise or something like
that mm-hmm
you know wholeness to it and then the
other meaning of the sense of flowing in
from a higher or greater hold or somehow
filling and fuck filling or orienting
choices and so you can imagine that
maybe those two meanings are not
separate they're the same and that we're
we're called to is is - grace is to
maybe embody grace into the world and
that the moment that you're about to
know enters into the portal that we're
passing through has the opportunity to
invitation - to continue to do that hmm
the so as you're talking about grace and
as you were describing it and pulling it
apart and bringing in your own
experience in the moment as it was
happening
while announcing what we were going to
be doing it just occurred to me it was
like oh yeah like this is very graceful
of you um
in gathering all of that together
while tracking what's happening and
holding multiple threads is very musical
hmm and I think I got curious about it
seems like there's a particular unique
capacity I've noticed that you have that
strikes me is quite unusual
in the way that you you bring in what
you're noticing in the present moment
as as the as the the about from what
you're talking you include what's
happening as it's happening as you're
describing what the
- and where that is moving toward and
weave that together in a very musical
sense like it has an improvisational
quality to it
I'm just wondering what wind how do you
do that I wish I knew that ding that
feels good lelouch yeah yes I think
simplifying the language would be
helpful yeah or I would imagine was it a
kind of thing that you were aware of or
did did you did it just start happening
and people went that they started
responding to it yeah but most of the
time not with a lot of smile of more
more rounds but with increasing smiles
maybe I'm getting better attitude the
world's getting more happy with it it
has something to do with oh so maybe
this is it it's something like if I if I
really really pay attention to what we
might think of as my primordial
experience it's extremely kaleidoscopic
and confuse it I suppose might be a way
of putting it
my basic experience has my sensorium is
not simple and the even like the notion
of like stream together moment to moment
isn't obvious like I have a very an
experience that time isn't necessarily
strictly linear my primary experience is
the time isn't necessarily strictly
linear so there's a practice of binding
experience in such a way that generates
a sensation of linear hereness hmm that
actually is from my perspective like
through my life has been in a practice
like an effort necessary to be in
relationship with mostly people by the
way I find that in relationship with
nature
there's nothing problematic you know
what I think challenging in terms of my
more primary mode the people seem to
really need to have things be pretty
linear and be quite flat in
dimensionality hmm and so a practice of
learning how to bring things that are
distinctly like my own personal
experience is being distinctly nonlinear
distinctly not flat into something that
more people find to be more pleasant is
it but beyond that all I can say is sort
of it's like exactly the same thing as
asking a juggler how they learned at a
juggle okay I could maybe give literally
my own personal here's the things that I
have done but it may not be a mapping to
me it all helpful hmm it sounds like so
couple things like let me see Mike if
I'm hearing it so one what I already say
is that there's here's a
which your experience shows up first of
all in in not in not very linear people
friendly right and that
you come into the context of another's
listening it calls forth it's like in
order to be with people in that way and
to communicate what's happening for you
what I think what I think I'm imagining
I think what's impressive or what I'm
hearing is impressive to me or stands
out to me is um is that you didn't it
doesn't sound like you went because it
seems like a what what most of the time
happens is that we get in front of
people and there's this difference
between our experience and what in the
way that it's asked others to be
presented as and I think most of the
time people actually stop calling their
experience real and they start calling
the the way that they talk about their
experience is real mmm right so it's
like it's more like I think that they
kind of damn you could say the map
becomes the territory and territory
becomes the thing that gets in the way
of the map being correct or not and so
it sounds really good this all sounds
really good
yeah so what I'm hearing you say is like
there's a there's a there's a I don't
know if it's natural or or there's a
particular proclivity that you have that
the the reality the complexity of your
experience which is like
multi-dimensional depending on what and
what way you look at it all happening at
once that for you to speak with people
or to share with people there's there's
an there you stay true to bit to the to
the actual experience of the territory
the experience and you bring it you
bring it into a constraint called
talking to somebody word after word and
it seems it seems but it seems like the
be authenticity part that I feel is in
your loyalty to your experience
that's nice uh-huh yeah certainly
doesn't seem wrong if something about
that it feels I could say like there's
like words like healthy and rich and
helpful um in terms of how what you're
expressing it's coming across right and
and then that the he when he talked
about like well increasingly brings more
smiles right and in the beginning it
didn't so much say more about that what
was that when you started having jazz
riffs we're the beginning yeah in the
beginning
haha well that in the beginning it was
actually very like well not the
beginning beginning the beginning
beginning is going to be in in
relatively early childhood but the place
that I remember and there's a like a
combination between the the feeling of
remembering it and they and the story of
it because it's been so much awareness
of that was actually at this really cool
summer camp when I was a teenager or
preteen at Duke University Duke tip back
in the 80s and being brought out of the
context that I was in which was like a
San Antonio Texas far the far far
northwest portion into this context
where there was a combination of I think
two factors I think really was maybe
three one was everybody who was there
was selected bizarrely enough on the
basis of having gotten above a certain
score on the SAT in fifth grade and I
meda selected by the fact that they were
aware of the notion that they chose to
participate they scored that score then
they chose to follow up on the offer and
had the money or scraped together the
money to participate
[Music]
then there was also a very large number
of cultural context that they were being
pulled from mostly domestic continental
North America although not exclusively
but mostly
[Music]
and then you had the fact that there was
an H age slice - it was very much
pulling kids at a certain age together
with the context of adults who again had
sort of chosen and had been selected to
be in that relationship and so there was
a
a lack of a prefiguring of what right
relationship would be hmm and a lot of
explicit experimentation by necessity in
a developmental stage that was quite
primed for that yeah so there was a
number like almost almost every there
certainly most conversations had this
characteristic of
liminality mmm no way of actually even
importing much context mm-hmm
even like sexual gender context because
you're at an age where a lot of that
stuff is very you not well understood or
known so you're not you're not you're
not coming with a lot of assumptions and
we're buddies coming with different
ideas anyway and so a lot of liminality
is a primary context and so then in
intrinsically just being afforded the
possibility of exploring in what is
available in this particular
relationship for what it is and with
individuals who had a to a greater or
lesser extent either a capacity or
willingness to engage in that dance
mm-hmm
the one of the things that is I've just
noticed and speaking and speaking with
you which is part of the rare part is
that you include the thing that's
available in the moment like the thing
that's happening right now is one of the
things that kind of makes it to me it's
really seeing but also it's very rare I
find because you know most conversations
have a have a triangular structure to it
like there's me there's you and then
there's what we're talking about right
but there's a momentary when you say I
notice being with you for example and
you and then you include where there's a
moment where it's like that the
aboutness becomes what's happening mmm
and that is a very to me that's a very
different experience the moment the
moment if well with anybody if you walk
outside and you want you want to
instantly get become more alive and
freak somebody out just go to the
cashier and just say yeah being with you
right now I'm just noticing the light
coming off off your cheek and if you if
there's a there's a quality of intimacy
that it Devoe's mmm is all it is pre
reflective we know exactly what's going
on and we know to be struck by it or
have a non neutral experience about it
and so I think one of the things that
grabs my attention about that you've
just found a way to do that in the way
that you do and quite often at least in
the context in which I hear you speak
given that it's so almost taboo to do
write that that you have found it to be
a practice upon which you have
cultivated throughout your life and keep
doing just strikes me as a certain kind
of necessity I just I imagine a certain
necessity that would have one be willing
to yes yes that's the that's the right
word definitely I was that's exactly
where I was I was going through all
kinds of stuff there but that notion of
necessity I think is exactly right
like a an obligation just but obligate
in the sense of you know woven into
moving so deeply into the nature that
it's just to be is includes that yeah
what is it what is it that you're
obliged to obligate right to be
obligated by what what is that wow
that's a really good question
come from a sense of I think one of like
really wanting to hear you so
also a
sense of
around like some of them this I think
it's more articulation and really
hearing I want to almost hear the song
that you're hearing that has you
[Music]
wow that is a really deep question
you
I just felt my heart that word song was
yeah holy cow there's something like I
mean the words that pop out are our
words that we have in our vocabulary ha
ha ha fun and I just realized now I'm
doing something that seen John do
several times which is curse the
impoverishment of our of our language
you know words like soul and was like
Damon and these the Peter is bringing
back into the vernacular I'm Tamera
delight words like well you know what
kind tell you a story please um a while
back not too long ago maybe like ten
years ago I was quite interested in
trying to imagine or explore the
[Music]
something along the lines of the the
notion of the singularity the the
technological singularity and way of
putting it as something like there's a
technology has a characteristic of
changing the possibility of agency and
we might think of it as an expanding
frontier of the capacity to move from
not being able to do something to being
able to do something at least in a
certain way mm-hm I remember sitting and
staring at a match head for a long time
and just imagining like what why is it
that I can't simply cause the match head
to explode into flame and why is it also
that I can actually just take the match
head and with the least amount of
intention swipe in a certain way it
explodes into plan like what's happening
at the distance between those two points
and as I was contemplating this notion
of what technology is has a change in
the possibility of what can be done and
that was just imagined as a thought
experiment what happens if we imagine a
singularity meaning that the capacity of
Technology increasing and increasing and
increasing the possibility of what can
be done becomes increasingly infinite or
or to invert we might say that which is
is obligate in nature because
increasingly optional in nature
well this then leads to a very precise
point which is what remains what remains
in that context you know so we could say
it's a thought experiment in principle I
could for example imagine a circumstance
where I could make expand my memory
computation to be able to have access to
the total memory on the internet right
that's not that hard but if I can do
that maybe I can also load my own
memories and have the ability to have
eidetic memory recall added but well of
course if I can do that and I could also
load your memories that's quite
interesting I can i could have
first-person experience of your memories
in principle i if the obligations of
nature go away and so what I ended up
having when I kind of did this to occur
sort of Cartesian reductio through
technology instead of inventing and on
the scene at omnipotent what was it a
genius genie
I'm actually just working through
becoming one what does it mean to be the
genie not to be the subject of the genie
it ends up with this sort of a singular
point mmm any other point that has a
sink that has a trajectory and
that seems to be a really like that is
that is this notion of the binding of
obligate dislike what is in fact simply
that which is irreducible as self so the
the quality of that and how we can even
think or talk about what the quarters
that might be feels a fruitful be better
done in poetry and see challenging but
would be the answer to the question that
you're asking
Wow
and I would imagine if we got it maybe
we would be the ones that go up in
flames
well well one way of thinking about it
is something along the lines of we're
getting it hmm through the process of
being thrown into the world like the
only way that we this is like you're
talking about thee you've always already
here like it's always already here is
the context of ourself we are happening
in ourselves to ourselves and as we
unfurl ourselves in the process of
actually simply experiencing and being
in life we're given the capacity to
perceive that which has always been here
[Music]
yeah and it's it's it's really an
interesting thing about you what exactly
am i perceiving like so that I think
maybe this starts to get maybe get it a
little bit of what you're talking about
or to unbecoming by it sufficiently
perplexed right which I'm constantly
seeking to hopefully be sufficiently
perplexed by the uncanny awkwardness I
find myself constantly in occasionally
admitting it I apologize I have a friend
Michael Vassar I was thinking about like
oh you know my oh great yeah I love
Michael as well that's the appropriate
that's exactly the appropriate
relationship to have Michael and this
this movement from like let's say like
curious to perplex to sufficiently
perplex and I was imagining like the
cascade like gobsmacked is up here but
then he has one where where it's you
know he just does that like okay that
one you've just got it that's the right
this to be waiver just happened there
that's the spark yes there's a there's a
exercise I do sometimes with with with
people to kind of on to see if we can
kind of tap into what it is the the the
phenomenological mystery of the most
simple thing in the world like called
looking at someone else right of like
what exactly to open that up right into
into experience the the mystery that's
concealed in that is what I'll do is
I'll like in my courses and stuff I'll
have people kind of like face one
another and then I'll I'll have like one
person look at the other person's eye
and I'll say you know at first there's
this kind of awkwardness right first of
all like you're facing each other and
you're looking at me and you know
there's all kinds of things that they
get triggered around that but like then
what I have them do is like okay now
look at the person's left eye
and then describe it in absolute detail
much as you can right and so they'll be
like okay so it's like there's a shiny
yellow glistening and then there's a
that's not totally brown it's like
greenish red and then it moves in this
yellow and they just get them in the at
some point they do that artistic switch
right and then I'll have them do that
for a in two three minutes until they're
kind of in the flow of that okay now
what I want you to do is let's keep
looking right where your eye is looking
right keep it right there and now what I
want you to do is instead of describing
there I just simply keep looking there
and see them and there's this experience
of whoa and then we go into kind of an
inquiry about like what exactly am i
seeing when I see you
you
what do you think it is
what is that
you
is it more like I'm apprehending you Am
I
am i because I'm looking my eyes looking
at the same place right now it the same
sensory prehension yeah that's good I
like that
and it yeah well it's it's it's like
this thing man again I think I only
broke either and I'm really actually now
that we're in this conversation enjoying
the way that the previous conversations
that I have now perceived because we're
in the moment we're flowing are melting
so I'm not quite clear right now whether
or not what I'm about to say is
something that I thought that I imagined
thinking that I imagined saying that I
heard you say that I heard John said
that I heard you and John said like I'm
not quite clear I something in something
one-one somewhere in that space but it
had to do with something like what was
it like the the total surface area or
the the truly enormous capacity for
awareness that is actually available and
the with the feeling of actually sort of
popping into something where and I
really look I'm in the power of the way
you frame that experiment that's the
ability to be like something around the
ability to be like focus focus focused
on a particular portion of that that
surface area of awareness and then
popping the whole surface of our
awareness open at the same time does
something right so what I would say what
I would say is that again almost as
always already I'm always already
perceiving a wholeness of you through
and via the wholeness of me but probably
particularly because it's a and
biologically revolutionarily necessary
and certainly we have been trained to we
dispense with most of it and we just
sort of focus on the parts that are
called practically relevant and so
there's a it's an interesting beautiful
constraint to create to unlock that or
or we re gonna lock to liberate to
liberate that that capacity to simply
realize that we can we certainly have
vastly more capacity
to be aware that I think we're usually
noticing hmm something like that
totally yeah totally and then Wow well
the other thing I noticed I just wanted
to share was that probably much more
meaningful than a set of words that I
just said was there a deep deep feeling
of like hard to explain
maybe bittersweetness or you know when
you let me know if this is because this
may just be my experience but when you
imagine the experience of your own child
or you're someone who is somebody know
and you imagine the experience to them
thinking about you after you have died
or simply if you simply contemplate the
reality of mortality and about the
infinity of the individual you're in
relationship with and simultaneously the
certainty of their finitude you know
there's a feeling that I have when I
imagine that when I'm sort of in
relationship with that experience as
that was the experience that I was just
having so mmm the feeling the quality of
feeling it in the feeling I just want to
make sure I don't know if I totally go
II just said so
the feeling that that comes with when
you imagine your child thinking of you
after your have died mm-hm like when you
imagine that that there's somebody I
love
thinking of me when I'm no longer there
when you imagine that
yet that feeling gets a vote yeah and it
comes with that at least it's a sort of
a huh an example it's more like there's
certain experiences for example I
remember one time I was taking a look at
Vanessa if you've not seen and I just
found myself actually seeing her age
like in real time I was just watching
her become older and older and older and
then eventually seeing her quite quite
ancient and that feeling in the heart of
in the moment passing away I think is
probably the essence of the good fact
that the fact of passing away in fact
that they're simultaneously such an
extraordinary amount of beauty in this
other person and now I'm back to you're
looking at somebody in the eye the the
instantaneous apprehension of the
singularity and simultaneously being
present to the reality of its
[Music]
ephemerality is that is that quality of
feel yeah that ephemerality
yeah just keep getting the sense of just
something like that
what I
phenomenology of
of myself seems to be a little bit more
like the more like a phantom limb
Langley that is in some ways it's really
highlighted in that experience I've
never really thought about that before
of thinking about yeah my son at some
point I'll be dead and my son is gonna
be thinking about me when I'm no longer
there
like at just this sense of this coat
this some because I think a lot of this
is you know I've been doing circling for
20 years and so a lot of circlings it's
been looking at the mystery of what's
going on in this thing that we called
talking and relate it seems to be
without it I don't even know I am like
put a baby on the island if it could
raise itself you know you come back and
be like you know are you doing it like
what say you
where's the you right there's this kind
of way in where it's it's very hard for
me to distinguish this sense of self
from this coupled um with earnest and I
think that there's something about you
know in a certain way that the you know
myself is a is a is an absence that it's
revealed in my in the revelation of
other Ness somehow and that in that
other nests is is you know that whole
thing with Harding aged Harding talks
about the headless the headless way
right where he's like where he realized
that if he took if he drew a
self-portrait
all he could draws the world right
fading into the background he never saw
his own face mmm-hmm your own face even
in a mirror right is not is not the face
that you live right it's the face that
others see so this sense of other this
is a kind of a phantom limb if you will
from these deep engagements that I have
with other people so there's this kind
of quality of well in also bringing this
back to what I was referring to with
with you that
when you share the impact of what's
happening with you in the moment and you
bring that to present right there's a
way in which it's so interesting there's
a way in which I find myself with you
being heard right because I'm aware of
something I've said or a way that I was
that had registers in the experience of
you being changed in some way right
there's a this kind of sense that
there's some way when you reveal
yourself and the in the moment
experience that somehow I find myself in
some way in your understanding ending of
the change registering with you mmm yeah
Wow that that sounds that sentence by
the way I don't know if you've said that
particular sentence before but it's a
very beautiful sentence which we don't
sometimes I reveal myself in your
understanding yeah yeah or since we
happen to be using recording medium I
probably did not say it perfectly I
think perfect would be a good way to say
it yeah it feels to me like there's just
something right about that there's just
rightness mm-hmm that's what kind of
what we're here for right right yeah and
speaking of speaking of what God is
going on this was let's read some of the
comments death our last video and I was
just really quite I mean I think one of
the things that I would say that what I
was really struck by was actually how
warm
in touch people actually people shared
their experience of the impact of
watching the video which YouTube is not
known for such warmth isn't that famous
for no I was just really struck by it I
just wanted to bring them into the
conversation here
one says whatever this was was one of
the most human things I've ever
witnessed
here's another one this chat was like
two surfers writing each other's waves
stopping for a moment to work out what
the heck just happened or discuss how
cool that ride and then doing all doing
it all over again two surfers having
intense conversation between sets
getting momentarily distracted until one
of them would say dude next wave it is
in love hmm
fun thing to do
try it sometime I think both of us have
availability the world needs a lot more
of this thank you for modeling it for
all to see
[Music]
cracking a well-concealed hard not open
unveiling the human heart it's fearful
tremblings its raw confusions and
putting aside the verbal in
conceptualizing armor of the mind master
and apprentice did you say it's a poetry
hmm wow you landed the thing the sacred
song thank you both but this wasn't just
a presentation for me it landed there I
landed there with you now flying
boom dropping in of the realization of
what it would mean to to deal with
Heidegger in the context of a group of
people in a process that actually could
enable the group to have a collective
capacity so what's going on for you
right now
it's like for me well one of the things
I think I could just take see what
struck me about it was the warmth right
of where people what I'm getting is that
people were actually touched in the
experience that they had in the
conversation that we have like it wasn't
just talking about the ideas but what
got heard right were was the was the X
in some respects that to listen to it
was to engage in the conversation in a
certain sense and be landed with us in
that way and I I would have to say I
think that that stands out for me
because I I just think that there's so
much there's a mystique like a
mysterious possibility that I feel get
it we're getting close to with this and
that that the that what got heard is is
showing us more can show us more about
what what it is that we're engaging with
in what we're engaging
in other words I'm really happy to be
talking with you and my heart feels
warmed yes I had the distinct feeling of
that um like ecstatic terror of doing
something that is like most it's like
falling in love yes
it's like something that is most
meaningful and something where there's
no way of being anything but just
exactly where you are in it
we knew that it what happens happen
mm-hmm and yet most meaningful yeah so
noticing that small high speed like
riding a bicycle very high speed down
the road where a small rock in the road
could cause a catastrophic crash hmm and
yet the kind of the lifting of wings
into the wind of the high speed and
feeling the elation of the lift and the
possibility and what you said earlier I
thought was really really powerful I
felt connected to something when you
were talking about the mysterious
possibility and I most feel I can never
like the responsibility or a an
appropriateness to not in that direction
right or welcoming also yes got so many
duty I felt that it but the terror at
the same time there's so many dangers in
it yeah like mostly the dangers feel
like ways in which I can mmm easily
convinced myself that we're no longer
doing that yeah or that you could never
possibly do it again
yeah yeah yeah which has had funny
because if I invoke the metaphor of that
was given to us of the surfers you know
that you surfed yes I it clumsily yes be
God enthusiastically and clumsily and
with a weird biased towards waves that
are much larger than I'm ready for well
once I
once I realized that I never thought
about it that you have to swim out I
didn't do it that much afterwards it's
not like waves in but I realize most of
it is so using that metaphor you the
experienced it that when you're riding
the wave you're really really well
advised not to be worrying about whether
or not you can ride that way and it's in
fact you know if you're if you're on the
wave the best thing to do is just to be
like really settle into it just allow it
to happen like the deck the duty of the
humility of recognizing that whether or
not you are ready willing able or worthy
of riding the wave mmm happening it's
happening again back to that notion of
grace like to be graceful in the context
of grace to be full of grace to be
listening to what's flowing and simply
flowing with it and allowing that flow
to happen without actually getting in
the way recognizing it has nothing to do
about you it's not your thing you're not
saying it or doing it or speaking it
it's not your responsibility
you're just how it's flowing it's
nothing to the world right right so
interesting you know it's funny when I
felt that kind of wave of Terror it's uh
it had a edit' tinge of something that
really reminded me of moments when I was
younger
where a actually when it hasn't remind
me was like it's not some some version
of the kinds of anxious attachment fears
that come up in a relationship of where
that and I've been at both ends of that
where right where I've been the one that
is avoidant and the person is you know
after me and I'm smothered and all those
things and I've also had the other one
where I was like really into them and
all of a sudden I can't tell if they're
interested and then I'm I'm tumbling
over right is very item I had a wave of
that I was like
yeah whatever this is it's that there's
some kind of I just felt an interesting
connection to look at and now that I've
actually now have an experience for the
first time in my life called secure
attachment write novel to me so novel to
me I'm struck by how simple and
beautiful and transcendent it is in a
very very rich way in my marriage and
I've never had it before so I feel as
though having it I'm I get to be have
like an adult's consciousness almost
like coming through the womb or
something like I get to track everything
in experience it's really quite a
surprising experience for me so it's
something that's really central in my
life is trippin out about being secure
in a deep way which has me wonder in
this dance right
with the conversation that are emerging
and the the mysterious possibility that
that we're listening into what is the
right thing to genuinely attack what is
secure attachment with this right what
if we kind of look at there be an
interesting way of looking at that like
what would be the correct place to find
secure attachment such that just like I
noticed having that in my life I'd say
my relationship to the world is a lot
more relaxed I'm more apt to make like
like really good risks
and encounter things and opened a
novelty that I wouldn't be comfortable
enough beforehand because there's this
place home that is ambiguous like the
center of the mandala is just wedded and
so that's having me be someone who I
continually surprised myself and more
like the kinds of novelties I seem to be
spontaneously open to that I wasn't
before this yeah
mazelTov has somebody who also spent the
vast majority of his life not having the
slightest we're not having an embodied
experience of secure attachments the
wave of existential relief that happens
when you actually feel the possibility
of it at all and then begin to actually
live in and then as you say through it
with it is an enormous gift I really
like that question came up in me as you
were as you asked the question she
presented the question presented is
better
and that we're the notion of home felt
like there's the if I if I imagine if I
mention what you went to new Brienne
Brienne yes mm-hmm
Vanessa I imagine Vanessa and I imagine
her and then what I do is I begin to
back away from imagining her is to
imagine the feeling that I associated
most fully with the moments where the
the unconditional Nisour the wholeness
or the invulnerability of the America
bility the purity of the love that I
feel from her all right not the love
that I know that I have the love that I
feel in this contact or this meaning the
secure attachment and then I continue to
back away from that and allow that to
actually become more and more what it is
in its simplicity and in its purity and
then imagine that that is simply present
in every moment without any particular
agent attached to it because clearly it
can't be attached to her right there's
nothing I could do to deserve that and
there's nothing that she could do to
give it rather it is something that is
always already present before and around
me and before and around her that is
available through us in our in the
quality of our relationship but if I
simply recognize that it's more a
quality of something that had vastly
larger mom and then wonder hmm and that
simply be the quality of relationship
with the moment could be a quality
relationship with every experience with
with everything with the world yeah and
then that's it like that feeling of
quality of the view of the quality of
feeling feels to me like that's the
place to be focusing and to be able
holiday feeling yeah yeah yeah the quiet
when I when I will said it when I when I
think about the quality of feeling or
the quality of the experience or the
quality or something you're right it
does it brings my attention to something
I'm in
yeah and want to go you know what's the
quality of the feel okay
I look back behind my eyes like here's
the quality of like yet it brings that
sense of as John would say like kind of
the trance well you know Wincott Wincott
would call it the you know the holding
environment right which it just seems
that the that there is a quality to
being that has a quality of holding
which actually gets back to that thing I
was talking about earlier the givenness
of sensation the givenness of already in
has his quality of like oh yes something
is giving for which I'm indebted to
right a way that I can't earn I couldn't
have even wanted right it's a I am he
indebtedness to it and every second
dance that's that's interesting
now
err where to find that place that is
appropriate to attach to is the quality
yeah just like where that brings my
attention it just seems like it brings
it to the right place
now
content it doesn't bring it to the
content it brings it to the context yes
the net place snack yeah yeah right at
it there is yeah that has a lot of
lightness to it a lot of push there's a
profound overflowing of various
anesthetics going on right now like
colors and shapes and sounds and like
giggling laughing and gellick voices
which I'm taking to mean yes yeah that's
nice like the you can kind of pit it
just be very like grounded very
practical and just notice say there's a
there's a way of thinking about all the
ways of knowing by the different aspects
of knowing and I can again be very
simple like just like the way that the
belly
knows like you know in a belly way and
there's ways it's the heart knows weight
the spleen knows with the the the
scrotum knows all the different ways at
the hands and everything else and
there's something about the quality of
the voices of each of these ways of know
anything actually when they all line up
right in your whole body like every the
whole body's going yes thank you
hallelujah like that's that sound that's
the sound of this the sound of
hallelujah is the sound of the wholeness
of self all at once and all of this
harmonious Felicity saying yes to that
mm-hmm that's a very good sign that's
what's happening
I'm probably on the right track great
make sure the W's in front of that on
the front of that word whole yes it's
funny I remember having this bizarre
when was it happen it was this it's the
relationships the older generation and
their experiences and there was
something that went on which of course I
wasn't present to in the sixties and
seventies and there's some phrase I
remember the phrase like if it feels
good do it that I think
a very bad rap I think I've got a very
bad rap because it it really radically
failed to have this notion of what it
means to talk about if it feels good
from a wholeness of self which includes
it feels even the least bit off then
slow the fuck down and wait and find out
how you actually bring that piece in the
hole alright so if you know the the the
the voice the language the logic is not
yet on board than the wholeness of self
isn't there but the inverse of that is
true like where else you gonna do like
if every single piece of you every
aspect of you every way of knowing and
thinking of being and choosing is all in
alignment saying yes then what is there
even to say that you would hold back
like there's nothing left to hold back
there's that's just being in the moment
in flow
I actually present to what is happening
fully and then you know that's the
dancing - the ability to dance and the
challenge I suppose would be to say can
we just not separate can we just not
have this notion of being like a
separation between mind and body or
separation between thinking and doing or
stuff like that but actually really have
that all together as a single integral
unit moving into the present yeah I like
what you said haha
if in doubt stop slow the fuck down
yeah and me curious too like it's nice
like if in doubt yeah and then shift to
curiosity as opposed to say resentment
like oh but I really want no yeah mm-hm
that's interesting you really seem that
that was a really good idea and yet
something is off I know that I learned
from that there's something about this
connection between the sense of play
curiosity and wonder and safety right
and I and I think that they're I think
one of the things I noticed and I
remember when I got this when I really
got this to hit me was I was it was
after one of the one of the courses that
I had taught and I was I was making
calls to the people just checking in
with them you know to integrate like
their experience and there was a woman
who had this really intense experience
which she had an enormous amount of
insight and went through a lot of pain
in order in the process of having it
right and there was a lot of content
that she got and I asked her about that
we talked about it and all that stuff
and I was like yes so what's it been
like like walking around during the day
and she said something she's and a lot
of her experience was about living in a
world that was already dangerous right
like as a not something like she
observed but something that she imported
right and a lot of it was just kind of
her seeing the way that she was seeing
it right and she almost independent of
that whole experience that she she had
she's like yeah I feel like just sitting
in
that environment of circling were all
were doing is being intensely curious
and in in wonder and interested in
what's happening just being in that for
three days I noticed I'm walking around
in the world and it just seems less big
hmm right less scary
and I and that really had me start to
realize like oh that you know you
usually like curiosities the first thing
that goes when I'm anxious right or I'm
pissed or I'm contracted in some way
curiosity it's like I'm in wonderment
about who you are until you don't give
me what I want and right then I get
pissed in that I'm like I don't I don't
have any curiosity I know exam right
that's that that triggered sense of the
word but I never had really thought
about that that actually evoking
attention and curiosity to the thing
that you're the most scared of or yeah
you're most contracted around that it
actually can have one find themselves in
a ground of safety like that curiosity
can be this thing that you can
consciously bring to it which i think is
what i heard you just say like okay slow
the fuck down look right get interested
in what's happening just that just that
shifting context alright oh yeah I mean
there's so many things there's like john
mentioned again in the past that he was
practicing something that i had also
chosen to practice a few years ago which
was first being able to distinguish
between what he called it a anxiety
style fear and a more of an existential
style fear ii to actually train himself
to actually use or orient towards
existential fear as a indicator of
precisely when to activate or flex the
muscle of curiosity hmm and i'm saying
all this words the way i'm saying it
because we read that's what you're
bringing up is that well if if something
about fear or rejection or conflict
collapses curiosity well then we can
imagine that perhaps they also or
they're connected there's a connection
there and we can perhaps imagine if we
if we learn how to how to build up the
muscles of curiosity then we can flex
the muscle of curiosity and actually
it'll collapse this yeah yes it's a just
capacity it's the skill set is a
competence and so you can then double
this down and say ah well now it's
happening so you're just collapsing this
what i may actually do
the option to convert this into a
perhapses it's more fundamental yeah
it's higher purpose and wishes to orient
me towards that thing which was
originally creating an aversion reaction
so now is creating a curiosity reaction
which is a more powerful way of
responding to it anyway right yeah
and this starts to have me think about
something like the religion without
religion oh nice knee we're in sync I
wit the same place huh which is not an
obvious fit spells Gong Gong yeah keep
going yeah just this sense of this this
sense of well
somebody I'd been obsessed with lately
st. Maximus the professor a a I think he
lived in like 700 AD he was like a a
Neoplatonic theologian dick and what he
he described you could say that what
he's talked about right was that the the
ground he what he thought was the ground
of consciousness what presupposed
everything about consciousness that
consciousness was a fundamental ground
of consciousness his what he called it
was a is a existential astonishment at
the givenness of being
hmmm like it I think the thing the
highlight there is is is it's not like
there's consciousness and then it gets
astonished know that there is
consciousness is an existential
primordial astonishment at the givenness
of being yeah yeah yeah that's neat it's
like the feeling I have is I'm listening
those words is like that that's that the
healing of a battle mmm like the peeling
of a banana but there's something so
astounding at the givenness of being
it's so astounding yeah but it literally
clacks open possibility yes like it's
just like yeah into yeah all right yeah
yeah awake so on some level what we're
talking about is starting with a
contraction oh I notice I'm falling over
myself
stop
notice get interested
that that thread back we start to get
into
very deep levels of of ourselves
like cuz you're following in a certain
law you're following a thread that
starts off of a cultivated ability to be
curious but if you keep following that
back right this starts to lead us into
these realms that have me think of
something like the religion without
religion yeah so it's we do this right
in you know Majan where you mentioned
secure attachment yeah and you met and
you mentioned the wood where I was what
I would propose is the highly highly
characteristic lack of in almost
everyone and then we talked about this
relationship of reaction and curiosity
and the possibility of inverting them
and actually building up the muscles of
curiosity and reorienting towards
curiosity as opposed to aversion and
then I was I was I was reflecting on no
wow what would it be like if we were to
actually be able to raise children for
whom secure attachment was always
already simply the case and for whom the
skillfulness of orientation towards and
use of curiosity was also always already
the case and we didn't have to wait
until they were in their late 40s to
begin to practice that in in groups but
it was already there their inheritance
in life what would that be like like
what would those people even be like
what would they be capable of that to me
feels like a real like design
requirement for the religion that's not
a religion and I personally am going to
be leaning into and signing up for
participating in or co-creating
something like that that's like okay
must do this right must result in this
yes go there yeah go there yes
thing really beautiful about that
because it also has I almost like a
sense of relief because the possibly the
recognition of the fact that we aren't
that implies that the possibility
I said this we can't it there's so much
more possibility so much more
possibilities available in humanity if
humanity is simply given the chance to
have these kinds of capacities from the
get-go uninterrupted the even things
that may seem really really hard and
maybe even overwhelmingly hard for us
probably just aren't ours our job is to
simply give rise to the people for whom
those things can be and to enable a
context where they haven't gotten harder
for them like that's again I think
that's a nice design requirement to say
ok we're doing something already mindful
of the fact that it's a generational
effort mmm we can then take a look at it
and say what is our piece of that what
is ours to do now as a generation and
how do we carry our particular cross
into the next stage so that the people
who come after us can continue to have
more and more possibility
if I
it's the D little experiment so a point
that at the wall across from me and just
say go say that wall just say that wall
that wall
he now point to it and say this wall
hmm this one there's there's there's um
Hey what I feel like is more of a sense
of in a very simple way putting it is
like talking about we're talking about
living into this world yeah that's a
nice shift isn't it yeah it's strikingly
simple but so
revealing in its immediacy of the
difference yeah yeah
because they think what happens is like
if I look at this that wall
seems to already have the identity
wrapped up and has this like pointing
out quality right where this wall seems
to point it something different it seems
to point at something like the coupling
of me in the wall yeah the opening to
relationship yes yes that's seem I just
wanna I wanna for anybody who happens to
be at this moment just to kind of like
really zoom in on that because there's
this MA ie so slippery that difference
that difference the the notion of what
it means for for there to be an interior
aura tea and a bringing of an again a
wholeness that's what it is right it's
that notion of a wholeness is a notion
of the difference between Oh God I
apologize it was mmm so perfect and so
beautiful but so many different things
were being pulled in at once I received
this apology thank you
I remember having a conversation with a
guy named Peter church's who is a really
amazing person with a huge background
but the thing he's been a longtime on
recent is called clear dynamics and he's
written a lot of books on why it is that
history works the way that it that has
worked so far in particularly the
problem of why it is that civilizations
have this really nasty habit of
collapsing and he noticed he pointed out
to me that the typically the way that we
end up actually keeping our civilization
together is that wall meaning those guys
over there who are not us and that we
are mostly defined by the degree to
which we're actually able to define that
which is outside of us that we pushed
against there's a push against miss of
that right and even if it's a notion of
going towards or accomplishing or
concrete as an energy to the bat wall
which has an energy to it that has a
primary C to invoke it I believe it is a
yang energy is that right
whereas when you shift it to this law is
a primarily in energy you know something
very different in that and the thing
that came up for me is that Peter and I
and many other people had spent a
reasonable amount of time thinking about
this particular domain of why it is the
civilizations of its national a bit of
collapsing and notice that there isn't
any real solution to that problem within
the entire metaframe of that wall mmm
and this can lead to a lot of concern
maybe more aware of the possibility
there being a different metaphor of this
law and when you shifted a different
metaframe
the inquiry becomes very very different
right right
it's it seems to evoke pure curiosity
yes hey you know it's interesting I'm
also kind of piecing together something
too about this the difference between
what my understanding or at least what I
think of one of oak's these two words
which is difference between an
individual
and a person mmm yeah be an individual
and two person mm-hmm right I think when
I think of individuals so in division
right I kind of get a sense of like a
bunch of I get a picture of a bunch of
half ba and half open boxes next to each
other
yep well I think about a person it seems
to be like a person seems to be the site
of the other
and in opening up the possibility of the
future of its future communion mm-hmm
there's something about the this that in
that in that frame and I think this is
now I'm starting to understand why I
wanted to bring in the comments of into
the YouTube and why they actually what
why those spoke to me because I think
what I felt um why I liked that right
why I liked the comments and really
enjoyed him was that it revealed
something that I didn't know that I
wanted right
that sense of you know that there's that
sense where I'm not walking around going
oh I want something but the moment
someone articulates or sees it there's
been something that's been listening for
it the whole time it just didn't work or
didn't have the thing and that there's
something about there was what I hear in
the responses is that that there's
something about the conversations that
are evolving that we're all having that
are revoking this is okay right like
this sense of like oh I feel like I
landed with you they said with you right
yeah yeah yeah more poetry yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah it's like um the
question the question is how is this
mysterious possibility able to manifest
itself right right and the the degree to
which you don't actually have awareness
of the desire is actually maybe more
like the notion of there's a quality or
an aspect of how this mysterious
possibility goes about manifesting
itself that you are not yet conscious of
it's always there it is what is
necessary it was it was necessary and in
green your capacity or presencing or a
possibility that needs to be made more
actual for the mysterious possibility to
manifest itself it's there it's part of
what is is necessary and as it becomes
clear it's like oh yes you can identify
it yes miss because it is of course
already real it is real but now it's
become real and notice it's become real
and actual and you say this business
that I'm there with you that's the place
we're trying to get to so it's actually
more like we're all kind of like
blindly kind of feeling our way towards
something that anytime light comes
through that lets us know that direction
that direction everybody can feel it and
right yes so we're all supporting each
other and pointing and saying yes and
pointing and saying yes and pointing and
saying yes and like okay we just landed
a little closer man we just got Oh got
landed a little bit closer on there with
you let's let's keep that that helps us
find our way in the journey of becoming
actually clear and awake and present to
the mysterious possibility so that we
can more and more fully and more and
more capably he'd be in relationship
with it manifesting itself yes and that
constant thing that like what being a
body is is it constant trying to get the
optimal grip on reality
right I think this is what job part at
least I I don't know if I totally well I
guess by definition I'll never get to
the bottom of the relevance realization
that John's talking about but I think I
just got a sense of it more of like yeah
what I feel right Oh interesting what's
happening right now is I do I feel
present to one I have to sell I'm eating
to self-regulate because I'm having so
much information right it wasn't as
socialized as I am it'd be it'd be a
problem um but like the sense of how all
of a sudden so many things from
different places are becoming relevant
to what we're talking about but there is
this quality of having there is a
quality of finding ourselves in it
having it already be there in some way
that we couldn't produce and that's part
of the danger is to try to produce it
mm-hmm
there is a sense of engaging in
something with curiosity and interest
and like in a wholesomeness but on some
level it the for example the religion
without religion
we've been talking about it before we
mentioned that we were even talking
about it on some level like it's like oh
it's relevant those things are coming in
and I'm noticing that as I talk about it
more the more the sense of cohesiveness
I feel and like a totnes about like a
totnes with it like something's coming
into
into grip right like it and like it like
not like a controlling way but like like
a dancer yeah again because I could like
two dancers intertwined yet that the
optimal grip is actually precisely that
ability to be in a relationship with in
other where the freedom of the other to
flow the direction the other needs to
flow is absolutely perfectly held while
simultaneously you are yourself flowing
and moving where you need to flow and
there's a kind of a give and a take
where this the softness actually gives
way and draw and draws in and signals
and shifts and pulls right that's the
that's the dance like it's becoming that
skillful in the dance right totally
another way yes I've got it goes it oh
yes actually I so do I really good to
meet you
I guess good to see you again I look
forward to seeing what happens next
I'm feeling more and more of it it by
the way it feels like a something in a
geographic place kind of in-between
where you and I are right now know why I
just had a fed of feeling of mountains
and song and ocean and sky yeah I'm I'm
good